Guide to the Julian Sorell Huxley Papers, 1899-1980 MS 050
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series VIII: Conference Materials, 1934-1965, 256690
  - Darwin Centennial, 1959; 256717 (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - Darwin Centennial conference programs, 1959; 256716 (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - Darwin Centennial committee memoranda and reports, 1959; 256715 (Box 108, Folder 3)
  - Darwin Centennial clippings, 1959; 256714 (Box 108, Folder 4)
  - Darwin Centennial JSH notes, 1959; 256713 (Box 108, Folder 5)
  - Darwin Centennial JSH comments on papers, 1959; 256712 (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - Darwin Centennial JSH comments, 1959; 256711 (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - Arusha Conference, 1961; 256710 (Box 109, Folder 1-3)
  - Arusha Conference clippings, 1961; 256709 (Box 109, Folder 4)
  - Arusha Conference Field Trip Guide, 1961; 256708 (Box 109, Folder 5)
  - Arusha Conference Julian's "Postscript", 1961; 256707 (Box 109, Folder 6)
  - CIBA Conference Programs, general information, 1963; 256706 (Box 109, Folder 7)
  - CIBA Conference MS and notes, 1963; 256705 (Box 109, Folder 8)
  - CIBA Conference JSH "Future of Man: Evolutionary Aspects", 1963; 256704 (Box 109, Folder 9)
  - CIBA Conference lecture manuscript, 1963; 256703 (Box 109, Folder 10)
  - CIBA Conference abstracts and programme, 1962; 256702 (Box 109, Folder 11)
  - CIBA Foundation 13th Film Session, 1957; 256701 (Box 109, Folder 12)
  - Royal Society Symposium on Ritualization, notes, 1965; 256700 (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - Royal Society Symposium on Ritualization, notes and MSS, 1965; 256699 (Box 110, Folder 2)
  - Royal Society Symposium on Ritualization, Suggested Programme, 1965; 256698 (Box 110, Folder 3)
  - Royal Society Symposium on Ritualization, abstracts and papers, 1965; 256697 (Box 110, Folder 4)
  - Royal Society Symposium on Ritualization, program, 1965; 256696 (Box 110, Folder 5)
  - Royal Society Symposium on Ritualization, JSH MS, 1965; 256695 (Box 110, Folder 6)
  - Royal Society Symposium on Ritualization, JSH MS - typescript, 1965; 256694 (Box 110, Folder 7)
  - Royal Society Symposium on Ritualization, JSH typescript, 1965; 256693 (Box 110, Folder 8)
  - Royal Society Symposium on Ritualization, 1965; 256692 (Box 110, Folder 9)
  - Royal Society Symposium on Ritualization, photos and proofs, 1965; 256691 (Box 110, Folder 10)
- Series IX: Organizational Materials, 256615
  While Series I: General Correspondence contains substantive and personal communications between Sir Julian and members of specific organizations, this series includes membership rosters, reports and newsletters, speeches, minutes and memoranda, organizational publications, notes, press releases and clippings. The organizations represented here reflect Huxley's varied interest in biology, humanism, eugenics and population control and conservation. Occasionally files overlap: the founding of the World Wildlife Fund is documented in the "Nature Conservancy" and "World Wildlife Fund" files; the Galapagos Island expedition is recorded in the Royal Society's Pacific Expedition Committee minutes and in the "Charles Darwin Foundation for the Galapagos Islands" file. Most items fall in the 1940-1966 period.
  Some organizations, such as the Royal Society and Eugenics Society, have fairly complete runs of material over a period of years; most, however, such as the Naples Zoological Station, are represented by only a few documents, or, as in the case of Unesco, several unrelated items spanning many years of sporadic collecting. Two files with perhaps the most original and complete materials are those concerning the Unesco "History of the Social and Cultural Development of Mankind" for the years 1948-1966 and a discussion group active in the 1950s, the "Idea Systems Group." Organizations which solicited Sir Julian's support also have material in this series - such as the Religious Society of Families, a eugenically-based community in the United States.
  Government publications and publications sponsored by an organization but authored by individuals are in the MANUSCRIPTS, PUBLICATIONS AND ADDRESSES BY OTHERS series. See also CONFERENCE MATERIALS for organizational material on specific events.
  - Abortion Law Reform Association, 1960-61; 256689 (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Aldus Books, 1961-62, n.d.; 256688 (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, American Council of Learned Societies, American Humanist Association, American Ornithologists' Union, American Society of Zoologists, Animals, 1964; 1961; (1949-) 1955, 1960, 1965, n.d.; 1960; n.d.; 1966; 256687 (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Association of British Science Writers, Association Internationale de Generalization Albert Einstein, Association of British Zoologists, Association of Scientific Workers, Athaneum, Bertrand Russell Peace Foundation, 1955; 1963; 1964; 1929, 1942; 1964-65; 1966?; 256686 (Box 111, Folder 4)
  - British Association for the Advancement of Science, 1937, 1939, 1965; 256685 (Box 111, Folder 5)
  - British Humanist Association, British Ornithologists' Club, British Ornithologists' Union, British Social Hygiene Council, British Society for Cultural Freedom, British Society for Research on Aging, British Trust for Ornithology, 1963, 1965, 1971-74, n.d.; 1960; 1951, 1952, 1959, 1961, 1964; 1925; 195[?]; 1949; 1942, 1950, 1951, 1953, 1966, 1969; 256684 (Box 111, Folder 6)
  - The Carnegie Institution, 1961-62; 256683 (Box 111, Folder 7)
  - Centenary Cultural Council, Center for Human Understanding, University of Chicago, Centre International de Generalisation, 1953; n.d.; 1964; 256682 (Box 111, Folder 8)
  - Charles Darwin Foundation for the Galapagos Islands, 1959-63; 256681 (Box 111, Folder 9)
  - Charles Darwin Foundation for the Galapagos Islands, 1964-65, 1967, 1975, n.d.; 256680 (Box 112, Folder 1)
  - Committee for Economic Development, Committee for the Study of Mankind, Congress for Cultural Freedom, Conservation Foundation, Conservation Society, 1960; 1957; 1950; 1960?; 1973; 256679 (Box 112, Folder 2)
  - Council for Nature, Council for Visual Education, 1958-63, 1974; 1950; 256678 (Box 112, Folder 3)
  - Discussion Group on Underdeveloped Areas, Ethical Union, Eton College, 1959; 1951-53; 1955, 1957, 1962-63; 1961; 256677 (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - The Eugenics Society, 1926, 1950, 1957, 1960-64; 256676 (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Family Planning Association, "International Campaign," Family Planning Association of India, 1960, 1963-64 1964; (1959), 1960-63, 1964, 1965, 1966; 256675 (Box 112, Folder 6)
  - Fauna Preservation Society, Fellowship of Religious Humanists, GLC?, Gandhi Gram, Genetical Society, Gesellschaft der Freunde der Biologischen Station Wilhelminenberg, Great Bustard Trust, 1972, n.d.; 1965; 1973; n.d. 1924; 1978; 1972; 256674 (Box 112, Folder 7)
  - H. G. Wells Society, Hampstead Artists Council, Harvard University, Division of Biology, Human Bettrment Association for Voluntary Sterilization, Humanist Broadcast Council, Humanist Council, Huxley Institute for Biosocial Research, 1960-61, 1973; 1954; 1939; 1963; c. 1959; 1960; c. 1972; 256673 (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - "Idea Systems Group" minutes, 1951-53, (1956); 256672 (Box 113, Folder 2)
  - "Idea Systems Group" notes, 256671 (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - "Idea Systems Group" invoices, memos, papers, drafts, 1952-53, 1950-51; 256670 (Box 113, Folder 4)
  - "Idea Systems Group" memos, papers, drafts, 1952, (1953); 256669 (Box 113, Folder 5)
  - "Idea Systems Group" memos, papers, drafts, 1956, n.d.; 256668 (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Organizations, "Idea Systems Group" grant requests materials, 1952-56; 256667 (Box 113, Folder 7)
  - Institut Francais d'Afrique Noire, Institute of Biology, Institute for Cybercultural Research, Institute on Science and Religion, Institute for the Science of Peace and world Understanding, International Brain Research Organization, International Committee for Bird Preservation, International Congress of Zoology, 1949, 1961; 1961; 1965; 1955; 1948; 1961-64; 1948-51, 1953, 1954; 1954; 256666 (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - International Humanist and Ethical Union, International Institute of Differing Civilizations, International Institute of Political and Social Sciences, International Planned Parenthood Federation, 1962; 1959; 1949, 1951; 1957-66; 256665 (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - International Union for Conservation of Natural Resources, (1948-)1958, 1960-66, 1971, n.d.; 256664 (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - International Union for Conservation of Nature and Natural Resources (IUCN), La Lune et la Vie, 1961; 256663 (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - International Union for the Protection of Nature (IUPN), International Wildfowl Research Institute, Isobar, Italian Refugees Relief Committee, Kenya Trustees of the Royal National Parks, Lebanese Association for Information on Palestine, Ligue Internationale de l'Enseignement, de l'Education et de la Culture Populaire, 1948-50, 1952, 1954, 1956, 1957; 1947, 1949, 1950, n.d.; 1965; c. 1927; 1960; 1974; 1966; 256662 (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - Lincombe Lodge Research Library, Linnean Society, Literary Society, London Natural History Society, Marine Biological Association, Movement for Survival, Naples Zoological Station, National Council for British-Soviet Unity, National Trust for Places of Historic Interest of Natural Beauty, n.d.; 1949, 1957-59, 1961-64; 1951; 1962; 1920; 1972; 192?, 1924; 1942; 1960-61; 256661 (Box 114, Folder 6)
  - Nature Conservancy, 1949, 1957-63, 1965-66, n.d.; 256660 (Box 114, Folder 7)
  - New Naturalist, 1969?, 1972-74, n.d.; 256659 (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - New York Academy of Sciences, New York Zoological Society, Ngorongoro Conservation Area, Advisory Board, Northern Rhodesia Game Preservation and Hunting Association, Oxfam, Oxford Arts Club, Oxford Ornithological Society, 1947, 1955, 1961-63; 196?; 1961-63, 1965; 1958, 1960; 1965; c. 1921; 1951, 1952-53; 256658 (Box 115, Folder 2)
  - Faculty of Arts, Oxford University Natural Science Club, New College, Psychotherapy Research Unit, Oxford University Humanist Group, Percy Fitzpatrick Institute of African Ornithology, Planned Parenthood Center, n.d.; 1923; 1960-61; n.d.; 1961, 1963; 1971; 1959; 256657 (Box 115, Folder 3)
  - Planned Parenthood Federation of America, 1954, 1959, 1960-62, 1964, n.d.; 256656 (Box 115, Folder 4)
  - Political and Economic Planning (PEP), 1939, 1942, 1953-55, 1974; 256655 (Box 115, Folder 5)
  - The Population Council Population Limited Foundation, (1952-) 1964; 1957; 256654 (Box 115, Folder 6)
  - Population Reference Bureau, 1958-61; 256653 (Box 115, Folder 7)
  - Population Reference Bureau, 1963-64, 1966; 256652 (Box 115, Folder 8)
  - Present Question Conference, Prior's Field School, 1953; 1919, 1963; 256651 (Box 115, Folder 9)
  - Prior's Field School, 1964-65; 256650 (Box 115, Folder 10)
  - Prior's Field School, 1966; 256649 (Box 116, Folder 1)
  - Prior's Field School, 1973-July 1974; 256648 (Box 116, Folder 2)
  - Prior's Field School, July 1974-January 1975; 256647 (Box 116, Folder 3)
  - Religious Society of Families, Religious Society of Friends, Royal Entomological Society, Royal Institute of British Architects, 1963, 1972; c. 1922, n.d.; 1964; 1962; 256646 (Box 116, Folder 4)
  - The Royal Society, 1941, 1949, 1953, 1955, 1956-58; 256645 (Box 116, Folder 5)
  - The Royal Society, 1959-60; 256644 (Box 116, Folder 6)
  - The Royal Society, The Royal Society for the Protection of Birds, 1961-63, 1964, 1965, 1972, n.d.; 1920; 256643 (Box 116, Folder 7)
  - Savile Club, Sierra Club, Singer Polignac Foundation, Societe Europee de Culture, 1962; 1959; 1958; 1950, 1950; 256642 (Box 117, Folder 1)
  - Society for Cultural Relations Between the Peoples of the British Commonwealth and the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, Society for Experimental Biology, Society for Visiting Scientists, Standing Committee on National Parks, Student Policy Movement, Systematics Association, Tanganyika National Parks, Uganda National Parks, 1924-1925; 1923, 1926, 1950, 1966; 1949, 1951, 1953; 1949, 1972, 1973; n.d.; 1953, 1954, 1961, 1964-65, 1973; 1959-1960; 1971, 1973; 256641 (Box 117, Folder 2)
  - United Kingdom National Commission for Unesco, 1960-1965, n.d.; 256640 (Box 117, Folder 3)
  - United Nations, 1949, 1951, 1958, 1960, 1965; 256639 (Box 117, Folder 4)
  - United Nations' Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization (Unesco), 1946, 1948, 1949; 256638 (Box 117, Folder 5)
  - Unesco, 1951-1959; 256637 (Box 117, Folder 6)
  - Unesco, 1960-1961; 256636 (Box 117, Folder 7)
  - Unesco, 1962-1963; 256635 (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - Unesco, 1964-1966, 1970-1972, 1974-1975, 1977, n.d.; 256634 (Box 118, Folder 2)
  - Unesco, International Commission for a History of the Scientific and Cultural Development of Mamkind, 1948-1951; 256633 (Box 118, Folder 3)
  - Unesco "History," International Commission for a History of the Scientific and Cultural Development of Mankind, 1952; 256632 (Box 118, Folder 4)
  - Unesco, International Commission for a History of the Scientific and Cultural Development of Mankind, 1953-1954; 256631 (Box 118, Folder 5)
  - Unesco, International Commission for a History of the Scientific and Cultural Development of Mankind, 1955; 256630 (Box 118, Folder 6)
  - Unesco, International Commission for a History of the Scientific and Cultural Development of Mankind, "Unesco History", 1956; 256629 (Box 119, Folder 1)
  - "Unesco History", 1957; 256628 (Box 119, Folder 2)
  - "Unesco History", 1958-1959; 256627 (Box 119, Folder 3)
  - "Unesco History", 1960; 256626 (Box 119, Folder 4)
  - "Unesco History", 1961-1963; 256625 (Box 119, Folder 5)
  - "Unesco History", 1964; 256624 (Box 119, Folder 6)
  - "Unesco History", 1965, 1966, n.d.; 256623 (Box 119, Folder 7)
  - University Philosophical Society, Viewers' and Listeners' Association, 1942; 1960, 1961; 256622 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - West African Institute of Industries, Arts and Social Science, West Wales Naturalist Trust, Wildfowl Trust, World Federation for Mental Health, World Health Organization, World Population Emergency Campaign, 1945; 1973, 1974; 1951, 1954, 1959-1965, n.d.; 1949; 1954, 1956, 1960; 1960; 256621 (Box 120, Folder 2)
  - World Wildlife Fund, 1961; 256620 (Box 120, Folder 3)
  - World Wildlife Fund, 1962-1964, 1970, n.d.; 256619 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - World Wildlife Fund, J. Paul Getty Prize, Zoological Club, 1974; 1961, 1962, 1965; 256618 (Box 120, Folder 5)
  - Zoological Society, 1938, May 1942; 256617 (Box 120, Folder 6)
  - Zoological Society, April 1942-Dec. 194?, 1974; 256616 (Box 120, Folder 7)
- Series X: Manuscripts, Publications, and Addresses by Others, 256525
  Materials in this series resemble those in the CLIPPINGS files in that their subject matter spans Huxley's interests: from professional and popular science to conservation and population control to fine arts, education, religion and philosophy. Arranged chronologically by year and alphabetically by first author within each year, the series includes articles from scientific journals, typescripts and galleys sent to Huxley by friends and colleagues, radio and television scripts, government reports on conservation and population, poems and topical newspaper articles on such subjects as photography and travel. Publications by other members of the Huxley family are included in this series.
  Materials whose date is unknown are arranged alphabetically and follow dated publications. Reviews of books not by Huxley have been gathered together and arranged chronologically following all other publications, several reviews are by well-known figures such as Stephen Spender and Arnold Toynbee. Reviews of Huxley's books are filed in the CLIPPINGS - Biographical Materials series.
  Folder 1 contains a list of the material in this series, which excludes papers presented at conferences which Huxley attended (see CONFERENCE MATERIALS), documents enclosed with correspondence (see GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE) or organizational reports and publications (see ORGANIZATIONAL MATERIALS). Much material similar to that found here is in Huxley's subject arranged BOX FILES. Short newspaper articles on current events and topics are found in the CLIPPINGS series. Note also that much of Huxley's library is owned by rice. Runs of journals and some pamphlets are part of this separate collection.
  - Contents List, 256614 (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - (1869), (1905), 1910-1919, 256613 (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - 1920-1929, 256612 (Box 121, Folder 3)
  - 1930-1933, 256611 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - 1934, 256610 (Box 121, Folder 5)
  - 1935, 256609 (Box 121, Folder 6)
  - M, 1936-1937; 256608 (Box 121, Folder 7)
  - N -, 1937 1939; 256607 (Box 121, Folder 8)
  - 1940-1941, 256606 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - 1942, 256605 (Box 122, Folder 2)
  - 1943-1944, 256604 (Box 122, Folder 3)
  - 1945-1946, 256603 (Box 122, Folder 4)
  - 1947, 256602 (Box 122, Folder 5)
  - 1948, 256601 (Box 122, Folder 6)
  - 1949, 256600 (Box 123, Folder 1)
  - A-I, 1950; 256599 (Box 123, Folder 2)
  - M-Z, 1950; 256598 (Box 123, Folder 3)
  - A-E, 1951; 256597 (Box 123, Folder 4)
  - Cantrel, 1951; 256596 (Box 123, Folder 5)
  - F-L, 1951; 256595 (Box 123, Folder 6)
  - M-So, 1951; 256594 (Box 123, Folder 7)
  - Su-Z, 1951; 256593 (Box 123, Folder 8)
  - A-J, 1952; 256592 (Box 124, Folder 1)
  - K-O, 1952; 256591 (Box 124, Folder 2)
  - P-Z, 1952; 256590 (Box 124, Folder 3)
  - A-E, 1953; 256589 (Box 124, Folder 4)
  - F-K, 1953; 256588 (Box 124, Folder 5)
  - L-Ra, 1953; 256587 (Box 124, Folder 6)
  - Re-Z, 1953; 256586 (Box 125, Folder 1)
  - A-Fo, 1954; 256585 (Box 125, Folder 2)
  - Fr-O, 1954; 256584 (Box 125, Folder 3)
  - P-Z, 1954; 256583 (Box 125, Folder 4)
  - A-F, 1955; 256582 (Box 125, Folder 5)
  - G-Z, 1955; 256581 (Box 125, Folder 6)
  - A-B, 1956; 256580 (Box 126, Folder 1)
  - C-M, 1956; 256579 (Box 126, Folder 2)
  - N-Z, 1956; 256578 (Box 126, Folder 3)
  - A-L, 1957; 256577 (Box 126, Folder 4)
  - M-Z, 1957; 256576 (Box 126, Folder 5)
  - A-G, 1958; 256575 (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - H-N, 1958; 256574 (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - P-Z, 1958; 256573 (Box 127, Folder 3)
  - A-Ca, 1959; 256572 (Box 128, Folder 1)
  - CI-G, 1959; 256571 (Box 128, Folder 2)
  - H-K, 1959; 256570 (Box 128, Folder 3)
  - L-M, 1959; 256569 (Box 128, Folder 4)
  - N-P, 1959; 256568 (Box 128, Folder 5)
  - R-Si, 1959; 256567 (Box 128, Folder 6)
  - Sm-Z, 1959; 256566 (Box 128, Folder 7)
  - A-D, 1960; 256565 (Box 129, Folder 1)
  - E-F, 1960; 256564 (Box 129, Folder 2)
  - G-M, 1960; 256563 (Box 129, Folder 3)
  - N-R, 1960; 256562 (Box 129, Folder 4)
  - S-Z, 1960; 256561 (Box 129, Folder 5)
  - A-B, 1961; 256560 (Box 129, Folder 6)
  - C, 1961; 256559 (Box 130, Folder 1)
  - D-K, 1961; 256558 (Box 130, Folder 2)
  - L-O, 1961; 256557 (Box 130, Folder 3)
  - P-R, 1961; 256556 (Box 130, Folder 4)
  - S-Z, 1961; 256555 (Box 130, Folder 5)
  - A-F, 1962; 256554 (Box 130, Folder 6)
  - Essay by Herbert Brewer, "The Population Problem in Relation to the Biological and Moral Regeneration of Man", 1962; 256553 (Box 130, Folder 7)
  - Herbert Brewer, Addendum to "Ethical Parenthood and Contraception", 1962; 256552 (Box 130, Folder 8)
  - G-P, 1962; 256551 (Box 131, Folder 1)
  - R-Z, 1962; 256550 (Box 131, Folder 2)
  - A-G, 1963; 256549 (Box 131, Folder 3)
  - H-R, 1963; 256548 (Box 131, Folder 4)
  - S-Z, 1963; 256547 (Box 131, Folder 5)
  - A-I, 1964; 256546 (Box 132, Folder 1)
  - J-Z, 1964; 256545 (Box 132, Folder 2)
  - A-Gi, 1965; 256544 (Box 132, Folder 3)
  - Gi-L, 1965; 256543 (Box 132, Folder 4)
  - M-Z, 1965; 256542 (Box 132, Folder 5)
  - 1966-69, 256541 (Box 132, Folder 6)
  - A-G, 1970; 256540 (Box 133, Folder 1)
  - H-Z, 1970; 256539 (Box 133, Folder 2)
  - 1971, 256538 (Box 133, Folder 3)
  - A-H, 1972; 256537 (Box 133, Folder 4)
  - J-Z, 1972; 256536 (Box 133, Folder 5)
  - A-G, 1973; 256535 (Box 133, Folder 6)
  - H-Z, 1973; 256534 (Box 133, Folder 7)
  - 1974, 256533 (Box 134, Folder 1)
  - 1975-78, 256532 (Box 134, Folder 2)
  - A-F, n.d.; 256531 (Box 135, Folder 1)
  - Ge-Go, n.d.; 256530 (Box 135, Folder 2)
  - Gr-K, n.d.; 256529 (Box 135, Folder 3)
  - L-M, n.d.; 256528 (Box 135, Folder 4)
  - N-S, n.d.; 256527 (Box 135, Folder 5)
  - T-W, n.d.; 256526 (Box 135, Folder 6)
- Series XI: Clippings, 256478
  Clippings have been left with related materials wherever possible; for instance, articles about Huxley's trips are found in the Series VII: Travel Materials. Clippings attached to correspondence have been left with the appropriate letter.
  The files are divided into two subseries: "Biographical Materials" and "General Clippings." "Biographical Materials" consists primarily of articles about Huxley but also includes vitae and bibliographies. They are arranged chronologically by year with reviews of Huxley's books separated and filed following the appropriate year(s) of biographical materials. Huxley's controversial activities and the public's response are well documented: his 1920 thyroid experiments, his Conway Lecture in 1930, the 1942 "zoo controversy" and his warnings about overpopulation and ecological dangers in the 1950s and 1960s. Reviews of books about or by other Huxley family members are also found here.
  "General Clippings" report current events, information on friends and colleagues, and oddities (labeled by Huxley). Subjects represented here reflect Huxley's varied interests in science, politics, the arts, religion and philosophy, including, for example, clippings about the Scopes Trial, population control and conservation and issues of African independence. Arrangement is chronological with dating following Huxley's notation: day/month/year.
  - Biographical Materials, [1909]-1925; 256524 (Box 136, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Materials, 1926-29; 256523 (Box 136, Folder 2)
  - Biographical Materials, Reviews, 1912-29; 256522 (Box 136, Folder 3)
  - Biographical Materials, 1930; 256521 (Box 136, Folder 4)
  - Biographical Materials, 1931-39; 256520 (Box 136, Folder 5)
  - Biographical Materials, Reviews, 1930-39; 256519 (Box 136, Folder 6)
  - Biographical Materials, 1940-49; 256518 (Box 137, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Materials, Reviews, 1940-49; 256517 (Box 137, Folder 2)
  - Biographical Materials, 1950-59; 256516 (Box 137, Folder 3)
  - Biographical Materials, Reviews, 1950-59; 256515 (Box 137, Folder 4)
  - Biographical Materials, Reviews, "From an Antique Land", 1954; 256514 (Box 137, Folder 5)
  - Biographical Materials, Reviews, "From an Antique Land," reviews of translations, 1954; 256513 (Box 137, Folder 6)
  - Biographical Materials, Reviews, "Religion without Revelation," 1957 ed., 256512 (Box 137, Folder 7)
  - Biographical Materials, 1960-66; 256511 (Box 138, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Materials, Reviews, 1960-66; 256510 (Box 138, Folder 2)
  - Biographical Materials, Reviews, "Essays of a Humanist", 1964; 256509 (Box 138, Folder 3)
  - Biographical Materials, 1970-75, n.d.; 256508 (Box 138, Folder 4)
  - Biographical Materials, Reviews, "Memories", 1970; 256507 (Box 138, Folder 5)
  - Biographical Materials, Reviews, "Memories," reviews of translations, 1970; 256506 (Box 138, Folder 6)
  - Biographical Materials, Reviews, "Memories 2", 1973; 256505 (Box 138, Folder 7)
  - Biographical Materials, Huxley Family Clippings and Reviews, 1920-56, 1963-68, 1974; 256504 (Box 138, Folder 8)
  - Collected book reviews, 1920-29; 256503 (Box 139, Folder 1)
  - Collected reviews, 1930-49; 256502 (Box 139, Folder 2)
  - Collected reviews, 1950-59; 256501 (Box 139, Folder 3)
  - Collected reviews, 1960-69, 1970-74, n.d.; 256500 (Box 139, Folder 4)
  - Misc. Clippings, 1906, 1910-19; 256499 (Box 139, Folder 5)
  - Misc. Clippings, 1920-29; 256498 (Box 139, Folder 6)
  - Misc. Clippings, Scopes Trial, 1925; 256497 (Box 139, Folder 7)
  - Misc. Clippings, Scopes Trial, 1925; 256496 (Box 139, Folder 8)
  - Misc. Clippings, 1930-32; 256495 (Box 139, Folder 12)
  - Misc. Clippings, 1933-39; 256494 (Box 140, Folder 1)